## Yong-Han Lin (she/her)

★ https://yonghanlin.github.io | ✓ yon9hanlin@gmail.com

## **Research Interests**

My past research experience in developing and evaluating a more intelligent smartphone notification system led to my interest in investigating the challenges in people's interactions with and reliance on automated systems. Specifically, I am interested in 1) enhancing user autonomy when interacting with automated systems, and 2) designing adaptive automated technologies that cater to personalized needs in diverse contexts.

Areas of interest: Human-Computer Interaction; Human-centered Al; User Empowerment

### **Education**

## National Yang-Ming Chiao-Tung University\* (NYCU)

**B.S.** in Computer Science

Sept. 2018 - June 2022 Hsinchu, Taiwan

- Overall GPA: 3.84/4.3 | Major GPA: 3.91/4.3 | Last 60 Credits: 4.07/4.3
- **Selected Coursework**: Data Structures, Database Systems, Operating Systems, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, User Experience & Usability Evaluation, CSCW Research Summer Institute

## Research Experience

# **NYCU Mobile and Ubiquitous Interaction Lab**, Undergraduate Research Assistant Advisor: Dr. Yung-Ju (Stanley) Chang

July 2022 - May 2024 Hsinchu, Taiwan

Conducted studies using the experience-sampling method (ESM), diaries, and interviews to investigate users' perceptions of automatic, manual, and hybrid notification management methods, and the findings resulted in a first-author full paper

submission to 2024 IMWUT (UbiComp) [C.4] and a poster presented at the 2023 UbiComp/ISWC conference [P.1]

- Led four students to research and build an Android notification system that provides automatic sorting and categorization capabilities by the implementation of the BERT model and Flask, while also enabling manually pin, sort, and categorize notifications [project site]
- Collaborated on identifying the impacts of customizing mobile notification alerts and users' strategies for customizing alerts through thematic analysis, the findings resulted in a full paper submission to 2024 MobileHCI conference [C.3]
- Collaborated on an ESM study of users' notification interactions in multi-device environments by conducting a literature review and using affinity diagrams to analyze the data, the findings resulted in a paper at the 2023 CHI conference [C.2]

## **Polytechnique Montreal Human-Centered Design Lab**, Research Intern

Advisor: Dr. Jinghui Cheng

June 2021 – Jan. 2022 Remote

• Conducted a statistical analysis and a qualitative content analysis to understand the usage, purposes, and impacts of visual artifacts in GitHub issue tracker system, the findings resulted in a paper at the 2022 EASE conference [C.1]

#### **Peer-Reviewed Publications**

(\* indicates equal contribution)

[C.4] Pinning, Sorting, and Categorizing Notifications: A Mixed-methods Usage and Experience Study of Mobile Notification-management Features [manuscript link][project site]

**Yong-Han Lin**, Li-Ting Su, Uei-Dar Chen, Yi-Chi Lee, Peng-Jui Wang, Yung-Ju Chang. Under review at ACM IMWUT (UbiComp) '24 (R&R Cycle)

[C.3] "I Want Lower Tone for Work-Related Notifications": Exploring the Effectiveness of User-Assigned Notification Alerts in Improving User Speculation of and Attendance to Mobile Notifications [manuscript link]

Tang-Jie Chang, Li-Ting Su, Yong-Han Lin, Jie Tsai, Zi-Xun Tang, Yung-Ju Chang. Under review at ACM MobileHCI '24 (R&R Cycle)

[P.1] Automatic, Manual, or Hybrid? A Preliminary Investigation of Users' Perception of Features for Supporting Notification Management [paper link][project site]

Yong-Han Lin, Li-Ting Su, Uei-Dar Chen, Peng-Jui Wang, Yi-Chi Lee, Yung-Ju Chang. In Adjunct Proceedings of the 2023 ACM

<sup>\*</sup>Former name: National Chiao-Tung University (NCTU)

International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing & the 2023 ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computing (UbiComp/ISWC '23), pp. 98-102.

## [C.2] Multiple Device Users' Actual and Ideal Cross-device Usage for Multi-Stage Notification-Interactions: An ESM Study Addressing the Usage Gap and Impacts of Device Context [paper link]

Fang-Ching Tseng, Zih-Yun Chiou, Ho-Hsuan Chuang, Li-Ting Su, **Yong-Han Lin**, Yu-Rou Lin, Yi-Chi Lee, Peng-Jui Wang, Uei-Dar Chen, Yung-Ju Chang. In *Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* **(CHI '23)**, pp. 1-15.

## [C.1] Understanding the Characteristics of Visual Contents in Open Source Issue Discussions [paper link]

Vishakha Agrawal\*, **Yong-Han Lin\***, Jinghui Cheng. In *Proceedings of the 26th International Conference on Evaluation and Assessment in Software Engineering* **(EASE '22)**, pp. 249-254.

## **Teaching Experience**

## **Teaching Assistant**

NYCU CS 1270: Introduction to Database Systems (Spring 2022)

Instructor: Dr. Yi-Ju Tseng

#### **Course Assistant**

NYCU General Education: Critical and Creative Thinking (Spring 2021)

Instructor: Dr. Jonathon Hricko

#### **Honors and Awards**

## Cornell, Maryland, Max-Planck Pre-doctoral Research School Invitation (Summer 2024)

Awarded a travel grant to participate in person at Max-Planck Institute to learn about cutting-edge research in computer science

## Taiwan National Science and Technology Council Research Grant Award (Fall 2021)

Awarded a grant for doing research on studying users' perception of automatic and manual notification management methods

#### Polytechnique Montreal Research Internship Scholarship (Summer 2021)

Awarded a scholarship for doing research on improving the usability of scientific open source software

## **Volunteer and Leadership**

## **Student Volunteer**

CHI 2023, Hamburg CSCW 2022, Virtual

#### **Team Leader in Public Relation**

Mei-Chu Hackathon 2020

Led a team of 6 students to contact corporate sponsorship and received 40K+ USD from Google, Amazon, etc

## Industry Experience

## **Software Engineering Intern**

Xaduro Inc. (travel tech startup)

Jan. 2021 – June 2021 Taipei, Taiwan

- Collaborated with the engineering team to develop a travel agency system that allows 1K+ users by using MySQL, PHP, and JavaScript [project site]
- Optimized the hotel reservation system by fixing 80% of the usability issues detected from Google Search Console

#### **Skills**

**Programming**: Python, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Java, C++/C, R, SQL **Software and Tools**: Android, Git, Firebase, Flask, Linux, ŁTEX

Last updated: May 28, 2024 2/2